telescope.com 2016-11-25

# Privacy | Orion Telescopes & Binoculars

## Privacy Policy

Welcome to the Orion Telescopes & Binoculars website, Telescope.com (the "Site"). Orion Telescopes & Binoculars has created this Privacy Policy in order to set forth the principles governing our information-gathering and dissemination practices in connection with the Site, including but not limited to such activities as the offering for sale of services and merchandise, as well as forums, chat rooms, personal profile pages, product reviews, article commentary, blogs, RSS feeds, newsletters and eCommerce, among other offerings (the "Web Site Activities"). Orion Telescopes & Binoculars has a strong commitment to the privacy of our Site's users. Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through the Site and not to information collected offline or to information you may provide to any third-party sites to which our Site may link, except as expressly provided herein.

## Information We Collect

There are two kinds of information that Web sites can obtain about you: "Anonymous Information" and "Personally Identifiable Information."

"Anonymous Information" consists of non-personally-identifiable data, such as your Internet Protocol ("IP") address or domain, or information about your usage of our Site that is used for administrative purposes only. For example, an IP address is a unique string of numbers that is assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider. Web servers automatically identify your computer by its IP address. We may collect our users' IP addresses for such purposes as to help diagnose problems with our servers and to report aggregate information to our advertisers, corporate affiliates and consultants, and to third parties that perform particular services on our behalf. We may also collect IP addresses as a security precaution when customers initiate orders through our Site, because although IP addresses themselves are non-personally identifiable, they are linked to information about you that is personally identifiable.

We may also use the information linked to IP addresses to ban users who violate our Terms and Conditions of use.

"Personally Identifiable Information" is any information that personally identifies you, such as your name, street address, email address, telephone number or credit card number. We collect such information when, for example, you enter a contest, subscribe to our email newsletter, participate in other interactive online activities such as forums, or order merchandise through our Site.

NOTE: DO NOT INCLUDE ANY CREDIT CARD INFORMATION IN ANY EMAIL OR LIVE CHAT COMMUNICATION. IF YOU DO, WE CANNOT GUARANTEE THAT YOUR INFORMATION WILL REMAIN SECURE, AND WE THEREFORE WILL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY LOSSES THAT YOU MAY SUFFER AS A RESULT.

Any and all of your Personally Identifiable Information (with the exception of your credit card information, which is always kept confidential) may be used to help us maintain your account, and also to enable us and our business partners to send you announcements of new Site features, special offers and promotional material. However, if you decide that you do not wish to receive future email communications from Orion Telescopes & Binoculars, you may follow the "Unsubscribe" instructions on the communication you have received.

If you purchase a product through our Site, your email address will be used to send your order and shipping confirmations, as well as other relevant correspondence regarding your order. We may also collect your email address if you order a product catalog. We may subsequently send you emails related to our products or services. If you do not want to receive product-related emails from us, you may follow the "Unsubscribe" instructions on the communication you have received or contact us as follows:

> **Orion Telescopes & Binoculars**: [sales@telescope.com](mailto:sales@telescope.com) or 800-676-1343

If you supply us with your postal address, you may receive catalogs or mailings from us with information on products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such mailings, please contact us as follows:

> **Orion Telescopes & Binoculars**: [sales@telescope.com](mailto:sales@telescope.com) or 800-676-1343

Also, as a customer of our Site, you may receive postal mailings from other reputable companies. You can have your name put on our "do-not-share" list by contacting us as follows:

> **Orion Telescopes & Binoculars**: [sales@telescope.com](mailto:sales@telescope.com) or 800-676-1343

Whenever you contact us in this fashion, please provide us with your exact name and address. We will make sure that you are removed from the postal address list we occasionally share with other organizations. 

If you are a customer of our Site, you may change your email information or your postal address information by sending an email to us as follows:

> **Orion Telescopes & Binoculars**: [sales@telescope.com](mailto:sales@telescope.com) or 800-676-1343

We may attempt to verify personal information to detect and prevent fraudulent activity including billing address, phone number and ship-to address information submitted with an order by contacting the credit card issuer, and using the services of LexisNexis and/or Cybersource.

FOR YOUR OWN PROTECTION, NEVER SEND CREDIT CARD INFORMATION VIA EMAIL OR LIVE CHAT. WE CANNOT GUARANTEE THE SECURITY OF EMAIL TRANSMISSIONS AND THUS CANNOT BE RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY LOSSES THAT YOU MAY SUFFER AS A RESULT.

In all cases, we will only use your information as permitted by law. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Privacy Policy, however, we may disclose Personally Identifiable Information to others if we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law or with legal process; (b) protect and defend our rights and property; (c) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the Site; or (d) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public. Please note that we may not provide you with notice prior to disclosure in such cases.

## Use of "Cookies"

Our Site uses "cookies" — data that is transferred from our Site to your hard drive for record-keeping purposes — to keep track of your shopping cart when you order merchandise through our Site. We also use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your password so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit our Site.

We use the following cookies and tracking pixels to deliver content, including advertisements on third-party websites, specific to your interests:

> **AddThis**  
>  We use AddThis functionality to provide you with the ability to share pages from our websites in your social media channels. In addition to a tracking pixel, AddThis serves its __atuvc cookie to visitors to our websites. You can find instructions on how to opt-out from AddThis functionality at this url: <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out>.
> 
> **Bazaarvoice**  
>  We use Bazaarvoice functionality to provide you with the ability to review our products and community items as well as read and interact with the reviews provided by others. You can learn more about Bazaarvoice's privacy policy and use of cookies, along with instructions on how to opt-out of Bazaarvoice data collection, at this url: <http://www.bazaarvoice.com/privacy-policy/>.
> 
> **Channel Advisor**  
>  We use Channel Advisor functionality to track activity related to those who have seen and clicked on our product listings at various shopping comparison websites. You can find information on Channel Advisor's privacy policies and use of cookies at this url: <http://www.channeladvisor.com/privacy-policy/>.
> 
> **Commission Junction**  
>  We use Commission Junction functionality to track activity related to those who have seen and clicked on our product advertisements at various affiliate websites. You can find information on Commission Junction's privacy policies and use of cookies at this url: <http://www.cj.com/legal/privacy_web_user.html>.
> 
> **DoubleClick**  
>  We use DoubleClick functionality to serve interest-specific advertisements on third-party websites to those who have visited our websites. You can find instructions on how to opt-out from DoubleClick functionality at this url: <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/opt-out.html>.
> 
> **eBay Enterprise Affiliate Network (formerly PepperJam Exchange)**  
>  We use eBay Enterprise Affiliate Network functionality to track activity related to those who have seen and clicked on our product advertisements at various affiliate websites. You can find information on eBay Enterprise's privacy policies and use of cookies at this url: <http://www.ebayenterprise.com/privacy/services_privacy.php>.
> 
> **Facebook Connect and Social Plugins**  
>  We use Facebook functionality to allow visitors to our websites to "Like" our products and pages. Information on Facebook's privacy policies and adjusting your Facebook privacy settings can be found at this url: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>.
> 
> **Google+**  
>  We use Google+ functionalitiy to provide you with the ability to share pages from our website in your Google+ stream. You can find instructions on how to opt out of Google functionality at this url: <https://www.google.com/settings/ads/preferences?hl=en>.
> 
> **Google Adwords**  
>  We use Google Adwords functionality to track activity related to those who have seen and clicked on our advertisements managed by Google on third-party websites. You can find instructions on how to opt out of Google functionality at this url: <https://www.google.com/settings/ads/preferences?hl=en>.
> 
> **Google Analytics**  
>  We use Google Analytics to track user activity in aggregate across our various websites. In addition to tracking pixels, Google Analytics serves its __utma, __utmb, __utmc, and __utmz cookies to our website visitors. You can find tools to help you opt-out of Google Analytics tracking and cookies at this url: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.
> 
> **Kenshoo**  
>  We use Kenshoo functionality to track activity related to those who have seen and clicked on our advertisements on third-party websites. You can find information on Kenshoo's privacy policies and use of cookies at this url: <http://www.kenshoo.com/privacy-policy/>.
> 
> **LinkShare**  
>  We use LinkShare functionality to track activity related to those who have seen and clicked on our product advertisements at various affiliate websites. You can find information on LinkShare's privacy policies and use of cookies at this url: <http://www.linkshare.com/legal/privacy/>.
> 
> **Microsoft**  
>  We use Microsoft functionality to track activity related to those who have seen and clicked on our advertisements managed by Microsoft on third-party websites. You can find instructions on how to opt out of Microsoft functionality at this url: <http://choice.microsoft.com/en-us/opt-out>.
> 
> **NexTag**  
>  We use NexTag functionality to track activity related to those who have seen and clicked on our product listings at NexTag.com and its affiliated websites. You can find information on NexTag's privacy policy and use of cookies at this url: <http://www.nextag.com/buyer/help/prPrivacyPolicy.jsp>.
> 
> **ResellerRatings**  
>  We use ResellerRatings functionality to provide you with the ability to review Orion as a company. You can learn more about ResellerRatings' privacy policy and use of cookies at this url: <http://www.resellerratings.com/faqs#privacy>.
> 
> **Shopzilla**  
>  We use Shopzilla functionality to track activity related to those who have seen and clicked on our product listings at Shopzilla.com and its affiliated websites. You can find information on Shopzilla's privacy policy and use of cookies at this url: <http://connexity.com/privacy-policy/>.
> 
> **Twitter**  
>  We use Twitter functionality to provide you with the ability to share pages from our website in your Twitter stream.

## Disclosure of Information through Business Transfers

As we continue to develop our business, we may buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses, and in so doing, acquire customer information. In such transactions, user information may be among the transferred assets. Similarly, in the event that a portion or substantially all of Orion Telescopes & Binoculars' assets are sold or transferred to a third party, customer information (including your email address) would likely be one of the transferred business assets.

## Third Party Web Sites

The Site contains links to third-party Web sites not owned or controlled by Orion Telescopes & Binoculars. Orion Telescopes & Binoculars is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third-party Web sites. Inclusion of any linked Web site on our Site does not imply or express an approval or endorsement of the linked Web site by us, or of any of the content, opinions, products or services provided on these Web sites. Even if an affiliation exists between Orion Telescopes & Binoculars and a third-party Web site, we exercise no control over linked sites. Each of these linked sites maintains its own independent privacy and data collection policies and procedures. If you visit a Web site via a link from our Site, we encourage you to consult that Web site's privacy policy before providing any personal information, and whenever interacting with any such Web site.

## Public Forums

Our Site may make chat rooms, forums, blogs, article commenting, and personal profile pages available to users. Please remember that any such information that you may choose to provide in these areas becomes accessible to the public, and also becomes the property of Orion Telescopes & Binoculars in accordance with our [Terms and Conditions](http://www.telescope.com/content.jsp?pageName=TermsAndConditions), and we may use such information in any way that we see fit. Consequently, you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information or to upload material of any kind onto our Site.

## Security

Our Site has reasonable security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Security of information communicated by or to us over the Internet is of utmost concern to us; however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Please note that your email and live chat communications, like most, if not all, non-encrypted Internet communications, may potentially be accessed and viewed by other Internet users, without your knowledge and permission, while in transit to us. For that reason, to protect your privacy, please do not use email or live chat to communicate information to us that you consider confidential. While we strive to protect your personal information, Orion Telescopes & Binoculars cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or through this our Site. Once we receive your transmission, we will use reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our internal systems. Depending on the nature of the inquiry, your communication may be discarded or archived.

## Web site security

We have taken many steps to ensure the security of your transaction. Telescope.com is secured with a GeoTrust world-class SSL certificate, enabling up to 256-bit SSL encryption. More than 100,000 customers in over 150 countries trust GeoTrust to secure online transactions and conduct business over the Internet. The presence of SSL means you can rest assured that communications (e.g. credit card numbers) between your browser and this site's web servers are private and secure when the SSL session is activated.

This Site is tested and certified regularly to pass the McAfee Secure Security Scan. To help address concerns about hacker access to confidential data, the "live" McAfee Secure mark appears only when a web site meets the McAfee Secure standard. This indicates that a site such as ours meets payment card industry guidelines for remote web server vulnerability testing to help protect your personal information. Click here to confirm.

## Policy Regarding Minors

Children should always ask parents before providing any personal information online. No information should be submitted to or posted on any Site by any minor (a person under 18 years of age) without the consent of a parent or guardian. Unless otherwise disclosed during collection, we do not knowingly provide any Personally Identifiable Information about minors, regardless of its source, nor is this information knowingly used by Orion Telescopes & Binoculars for any marketing or promotional purposes. Minors are not eligible to participate in contests on the Sites, unless expressly provided to the contrary.

Orion Telescopes & Binoculars abides by the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act. In the event that we learn that we have collected information from any child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete this information from our database as quickly as reasonably possible. If you believe that our Site has collected any information about anyone under 13, please contact Orion Telescopes & Binoculars' Site Administrator via postal mail or email at one of the addresses listed below.

## Limitation of Liability 

ORION TELESCOPES & BINOCULARS PROVIDES THE INFORMATION, SERVICES AND PRODUCTS ON THIS WEB SITE "AS IS" WITHOUT WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND. YOU AGREE THAT ORION TELESCOPES & BINOCULARS SHALL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY CONTENT FOUND ON OUR FORUMS, THAT YOUR USE OF ANY OF OUR FORUMS, THAT ANY DOWNLOADING OF MATERIALS FOUND ON OR THROUGH THE ORION TELESCOPES & BINOCULARS SITE'S FORUMS IS DONE AT YOUR OWN RISK, AND THAT ORION TELESCOPES & BINOCULARS IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR UNSOLICITED COMMUNICATIONS THAT ARISE FROM YOUR POSTINGS ON OUR SITE. ORION TELESCOPES & BINOCULARS SHALL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE IN ANY MANNER FOR THE ACTS OF ANY THIRD PARTY, INCLUDING WITOUT LIMITATION, ANY THIRD PARTY AD NETWORK.

## Consent and Modifications to this Privacy Statement

The Site is controlled, operated and administered entirely within the United States. By using our Site, you signify your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Statement. If you do not agree with this Privacy Statement, please do not disclose any personal information through our Site. Orion Telescopes & Binoculars may modify this Privacy Statement at any time, at its discretion, and modifications are effective upon being posted on this the applicable Site. You are responsible for reviewing this Privacy Statement periodically to ensure that you are aware of any changes to it.

## Contacting Orion Telescopes & Binoculars

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, the practices of our Site, or your dealings with this Site, you may contact us at:

> Site Administrator  
>  Orion Telescopes & Binoculars  
>  89 Hangar Way  
>  Watsonville, CA 95076  

This Privacy Policy is effective as of December 5, 2014.
